Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut (1910-2003) 1738-2006 AR 25309 / MF 932
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series I: W. Gunther Plaut Genealogy, 1738-2005; 7.875 linear feet.
  - Subseries 1: Locations, 1738-2005; 5.625 linear feet.
    - F) Ottrau
      - Correspondence - Plaut, [Feist] Frederick - Descendants, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 66)
        Plaut, Jonathan 1984
        Plaut, Abraham L. and Beverly 1977-1986
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Feist (Frederick) - Descendants, 1982-1990 (Box 2, Folder 67)
        Holzmann, Caryll 1983-1984
        Rose, Sanford ("Sandy") 1982-1986
        Rosenberg, Merwin 1982-1990
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Feist (Frederick) - Descendants - Fred Neisner, 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Tilo, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Family Trees, undated, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Family Trees - Complete, 1991, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Katz, 1982-1986, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Katz - Beiseforth, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Research - Salomon Plaut, 1738, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - G) Rauschenberg
      - Baird, Carol [Davidson] - Articles and Notes, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1853, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Plaut, Arthur 1974-1977
        Plaut, Ascher 1980-1981
        Plaut, David 1976-1983
        Plaut, Herbert 1981-1983
        Plaut, Manfred (Bachenheimer Agreement) 1853, 1974-1975
      - Correspondence, 1973-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
        Budow, Maury 1977-1979
        Cohen, Ruth 1973
        Kadden, Adele 1985
        Ransenberg, Selma 1973-1984
      - Correspondence, 1973-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        Frank, Helene 1981-1992
        Frankel, Edie 1986-1991
        Plaut, Evelyn 1973
        Plaut, Martin and Ida 1989
        Plaut, Samuel M. 1973
        Rapp, Greta? 1973-1974
        Wolf, Erwin M. 1988
        Wolf, Henry 1974
      - Correspondence, 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
        Plaut, David 1984
        Plaut, Martin and Ida 1973-1991
        Plaut, Steven 1980-1995
      - Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        Frankel, Edie 1983-1992
        Hess, Fritz 1984
        Rhine, Judith Plaut 1984
        Strauss-Neuhaus, Lillian 1983-1984
      - Correspondence - Baird, Carol Davidson, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence - Baker, Ruth Sinberg - Plaut/ Blaut/ Blout Research, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence - Berman, Susie, 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence - Blout, Isaac and Henry - Branch, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        Abel, Marjorie 1976
        Auerbach, Moses 1981-1982
        Falk, Edna 1979
        Fedder, Betty 1981-1982
        Greenberg, Rose 1981
        Hyman, Muriel 1984
        Putzel, Janith 1978-1981
        Sack, Sallyann Amdur 1982
        Sage, Selma Z. 1977
        Simon, Jane 1976-1982
      - Correspondence - Frank, Helene, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence - Frank, Helene, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence - Frank, Helene, 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence - Hyman, Muriel - Abraham and Mathilde Plaut Branch, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence - Indiana Jewish Historical Society (Joseph Levine), 1979-1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence - Kadden, Bruce and Adele, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence - North, Stephen, 1977-1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence - Palti Family, 1973-1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        Palti, Amos (Walter Plaut) 1973-1983
        Palti, Hagai 1974, 1985
        Unidentified family member 1993
      - Correspondence - Rapp, Greta, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence - Research - Emmanuel Blout and Sarah Solomon, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
        Canadian Jewish Congress 1987
        National Archives of Canada 1988
        Stewart, Ruth 1987-1988
      - Correspondence - Rose, Sanford - Simon Plaut Photograph, 1929, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence - Wolf, Henry and Erwin, 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Family Trees - Early Records - Chaim (Heinemann) Plaut Tree, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Amshel Michael Simon, 1980s? (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Isaac and Sara Plaut Stiefel, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Michael Simon, 1982-1986, 1990s? (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Michael Simon - Correspondence, 1974-1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        Frank, Helene 1983
        Plaut, Martin and Ida 1988
        Wolf, Fred 1974
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Katz/ Stiefel, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Solomon, undated, 1973-1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Stiefel, 1934, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Plaut, Walter - Eulogies, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - H) Reichensachsen
      - Bender, Edgar - Family Photographs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - BMD [Birth, Marriage, and Death?] Records, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 39)
        Leighton, Fred V. 1977-1980
        Plaut, Erwin 1976-1979
        Plaut, Herbert 1974-1976
        Stern, Harriet E. 1974-1976
      - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        Liebeshutz, Hugo 1988
        Plaut, G.S. 1990-1992
        Sprinz, Hugo 1988-1990
      - Correspondence - Frankel, Paul, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence - Hallo, Bill, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence - Liebesschuetz, Rachel, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence - Max Plaut Research, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence - Mayer, Frederico, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence - Ogden, Jehiel, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Family Trees, undated, 1974-1976, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Family Trees - Cincinnati, 1980s? (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, David Jacob Kusel - Descendants, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Family Trees - Eric Plaut (England), undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Family Trees - Felix Plaut Branch - Correspondence - Katz, Bernice and Ruth, 1974-1987 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Family Trees - Lein and Fink, 1973-1989, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Family Trees - Lein and Fink - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 3, Folder 53)
        Herzig, Donald P. 1982
        Kahn, Jean 1975
        Kotkin, Jean S. 1979
        McDermott, James 1980
        Plaut, Walter 1974-1988
        Society for Ethical Culture 1979
      - Family Trees - Lein and Fink - Correspondence - Herzig, Donald P. and Gwen, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Family Trees - Lein and Fink - Correspondence - Plaut, Walter, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Family Trees and Correspondence - Plaut and Liebesschutz Families, 1980s?-1987 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - Notes - Index Cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Plaut, Clara - Memoir, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Research Notes, 1958, 1974-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Research Notes - Correspondence, 1973-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - I) Rotenburg an der Fulda
      - Correspondence - Cohen, Marion, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence - Lewis, Steven, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Herbert and Edith, 1972-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Jules and Ellen, 1968-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Family Trees with Notes, 1973-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Plaut, Heinemann - Research - Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1951-1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Research - Documentation and Notes, undated, 1824-1873 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - J) Schenklengsfeld
      - Cemetery Records, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1979, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        Goldsmith, Selma Plaut 1976-1979
        Hallo, Michael 1979
        Maibaum, Jean 1975
        Plaut, Eric 1975-1979
        Plaut, Herman 1973
        Plaut, Kurt 1973
        Plaut, Lina 1979
        Plaut, Rosi 1973
        Scheuer, Trudel 1973
        Weinberg, Bernd 1989
      - Correspondence, 1976-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        Poloway, Anne 1981
        Wallace, Margot and Henry 1987-1991
        Wimpfheimer, Aaron 1981
      - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        Honikel, Karl 1988-1989
        Lowenberg, Hans 1989
        Plaut, Marion 1988-1989
        Steiner, M. 1988
        Wallace, Henry 1988
      - Correspondence - Anderson, Jill S., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family, 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
        Fishman, Felix A. 1984
        Plaut, Harry 1977
        Plaut, Herbert Hans 1977-1986
        Plaut, Howard 1984
      - Correspondence - Plaut, H. Naftali, 1973-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Itai, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1973-1988, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        Mainzer, Martin 1988
        Plaut, Hermann 1973
        Plaut, Lina 1975
        Plaut, Rahel 1974
        Wallace, Henry 1982
        Wimpheimer, Aaron 1981
        Wolf, Hilla 1974
      - Correspondence and Notes - Katz, Walter, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Family Trees, 1988-1994, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Family Trees - Margot Wallace, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Family Trees - Original Stammbaum, undated, 1977, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Family Trees - Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - K) Schmalkalden
      - Correspondence - Dannenberg, James, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence - Dibowitz, Ilse ("Blackie"), 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence - Mainzer, Martin, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Julio (Santiago, Chile), 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Louis (Sao Paulo), 1979, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Holstein Family Members, 1971, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Family Trees, undated, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Family Trees - Plauts and Plautbergs, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Kass, Beine (Brunchen) - Ancestors, 1980s?, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Notes, 1979, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Notes - Judemann Plaut Branch, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Plaut, Moses Juda and Joseph - Descendants, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - L) Wehrda
      - Correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
        Plaut, Henry Steven 1979-1985
        Plaut, Louise 1976
      - Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
        Kobren, Leonore 1984
        Plaut, Alfred 1978-1985
        Plaut, Bertel 1984-1985
        Plaut, Harvey 1985-1988
        Plaut, Warren W. 1984
        Weiss, Kenneth J. 1985
      - Correspondence - Friend/ Freund Families (Hartford), 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
        Friend, Herbert 1974-1990
        Hermann, Bernice L. 1976
        Stern, Morton 1981
        Rodel, Mrs. [Unidentified] 1979
        Hanreck, Mr. [Unidentified] 1979
        Plaut, Israel 1976
      - Correspondence - Froehlich and Salavitch Families, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence - Hartford, 1973-1984 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Correspondence - Hartford Research, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Bertha and Herman Abraham Descendants - Desirée Barnett, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, David and Sidney, 1973-1986 (Box 4, Folder 45)
        Plaut, David 1977--1979
        Plaut, Sidney 1973-1986
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Isidor and Sara Harris - Branch, 1977-1993 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence - Research - Hartford, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Correspondence - Schwartz, Belle and Regina Schwartz McCoy, 1973-1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
        McCoy, Regina Schwartz 1979-1984
        Schwartz, Belle 1977-1980
      - Correspondence - Stern Family Members, 1974-1986 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence - Stern, Solomon - Branch, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence and Research - Roth, Emery and Jane, 1981-1984, 5004 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Data from Others - Correspondence and Notes, 1973-1990 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Documentation - Julius Plaut Family (Hartford), 1887-1892, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Katzenstein Relationships, 1990s? (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Michael (Marum) - Early Charts, undated, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Ruben (Hartford), undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Simon and Malchen (Malke/ Malka), 1974-1991, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Simon and Malchen (Malke/ Malka) - Correspondence, 1973-1997 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Simon and Malchen (Malke/ Malka) - Ruben Moses Plaut, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Family Trees - Stern Family, 1980s?, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Family Trees - Stern, Solomon and Jette Nathan, 1900, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Family Trees - Various Branches, undated, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Hess, Marjorie Stern - Memoir, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Notes - Connecticut (Hartford/ Danbury/ Norwich), 1980-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Notes - Diagnosis, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Notes and Correspondence, 1846, 1973-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Notes and Correspondence - Friend/ Freund Family, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Plaut, David - Research (New Jersey and Connecticut), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Plaut, Madelyn - Research (Hamden, CT), 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Plaut/ Stern Data, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Records - Notes, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Simon and Malchen (Malke) Plaut Branch - Newark, 1909-1950, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Stern Family - Records and Notes, undated, 1974-1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - M) Willingshausen
      - Announcements, Invitations, and Family Photographs, 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Borowsky, Bertel Kugelman - Memoir, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Clippings, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Clippings - Jonas Plaut, undated, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence - Cemetery Inquiries - Mount Hope Cemetery (Brooklyn, NY), 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence - Felix Uhry Research - Rosalie Rosenfeld, 1855-1932, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence - Herman Plaut Branch, 1973-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence - Hoos, Heinrich, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence - Joseph Lovi [Loevi?] Plaut Branch, 1973-1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence - Joseph Loevi Plaut Branch, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence - Laband, Esther (Max Spier Family), 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence - Meyer, David, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Cormi, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Max and Ruth, 1972-1990 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Raphael and Ruth - Rundbriefe, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence - Raphael Levi [Loevi?] Plaut Branch, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence - Raphael Loevi Plaut Branch, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence - Rosenfeld, Rosalie, 1975-1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence - Sophie Joseph Plaut/ Wolf Gruenebaum Branch, 1973-1991 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence - South Africa, 1973-1984 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence - South Africa - Plaut, Gertie, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence - South Africa - Plaut, Rebecca ("Becky"), 1973-1987 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence - Spier/ Plaut Family Tree, 1973-1979 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence - Spier/ Plaut Family Tree - Hannah Lichtenstein, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees - Holstein Family, 1978-1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Moses Raphael Plaut Branch, 1972-1992 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Plaut, Tilotty ("Tilo"), undated, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Correspondence and Research - Wachtel Family, 1979-1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence, Notes, and Documentation, 1851-1852, 1976-1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Diagnosis, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Documentation - Death and Marriage Certificates, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Family Trees, 1972-1990s, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Family Trees - Heilbrumm Family - Spier and Koenig Trees, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Family Trees - Initial Notes, 1989-1998 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Family Trees - Loevi and Syphra Landauer Plaut Descendants, undated, 1957, 1989-1995 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Family Trees - Loevi (Lovi) Plaut, 1976-1997 (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Family Trees - Notes - Spier/ Plaut, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Family Trees - W. Gunther Plaut Family, 1942-1964, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Moses Joseph Plaut Branch - Correspondence, 1985-1992 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Moses Joseph Plaut Branch - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1974-1992 (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Norwich (CT) Plauts, 1877, 1956-1982 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Photographs and Postcards, undated, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Plaut, Abraham - Research - Correspondence, Notes, and Memoir, 1967-1991 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Plaut, Joseph Raphael - Research, 1877, 1974-1981 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Plaut, Raphael - American Descendants - Correspondence - Ed and Carol Plaut, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Plaut Family Members - Clippings and Notes, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Research - Documentation and Notes, 1879-1987 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Saxe Genealogy, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Spier and Saxe Genealogy, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - N) Other Locations
      - Abterode, undated, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Allendorf, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Beiseforth, 1976-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Beiseforth and Netra, undated, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Bodenteich, undated, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Bonn, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Bovenden, 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Bovenden - Victor Plaut Research - Correspondence, 1976-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Darmstadt and Hunfeld, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Duisberg, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Eschwege - Death and Marriage Records, 1825-1936 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Eschwege - Notes and Documentation, undated, 1806, 1974-1989? (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Falkenberg, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Falkenberg - Goldschmidt/ Goldsmith Family, 1978-1987, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Felsberg, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - France - Names of French Jews, undated, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Frankershausen, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Frankershausen - Birth, Death, and Marriage Registries, 1738-1852 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Fulda, 1937, 1973-1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Fulda - Correspondence and Notes - Frania Neumann, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Gehaus, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - German Cemeteries, 1980? (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Giessen - Correspondence and Family Tree, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Gießen and Harmutsachen, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Goßfelden - Descendants of Samuel Loelyenstein and Goddel, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Gudensberg/ Felsberg, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Guxhagen, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Guxhagen - Family Trees, undated, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Halberstadt, undated, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Hamburg, 1974-2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Holland, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Jerusalem, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Jerusalem - Central Archives for the History of the Jewish People (Sprinzak Building, Hebrew University), 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Locations A-T, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Locations A-W, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Melsungen, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Melsungen - Family Trees - Levi Abraham Plaut Branch, 1973-1978, 1990s? (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Melsungen - Family Trees - Sandel Katz and Hannah Kaufmann, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Melsungen - Katz/ Plaut Relationships - Family Trees, undated, 1975, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Melsungen - Weinreb, Daniel - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - erzhausen - Family Tree - Isaac Spier and Gertrud Bacherach, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Merzhausen - Records, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Merzhausen - Research - Schwalmer Jahrbuch, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Mollenfeld - Plaut, Thomas A. - Correspondence, 1936, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Mollenfeld and Bodenteich - Documentation, 1893-1936, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Neukirchen - Nussbaum and Oeilchen Family Members, 1897, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Neukirchen - Plaut Family Members, 1975-1993 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Niederaula, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - Niedenstein, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - Nordhausen, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Oberaula, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Ottrau - Correspondence, 1974-1989 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Ottrau - Notes and Documentation, 1974-1986 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Schrecksbach - Spier Family Members - Notes, undated, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Spangenberg, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Storndorf - Correspondence - Ruth Bierman, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Stuttgart and Ludwigsburg, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Unidentified Location - Correspondence - Hallo, Gertrude, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Witzenhausen, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Subseries 2: Other Research Files, 1860-2006; 1.25 linear feet.
    Divided into Correspondence;Notes, Family Trees, and Collected Documentation; and files originally left Unsorted.
    Subseries 2 holds the research files pertaining to the Plaut family that were not originally ordered by location. During processing these files were grouped together by document genre and files Elizabeth Strauss Plaut left unsorted. Untitled folders or those labeled "various" were assigned titles during processing.
    Correspondence found in this subseries is with family members and research institutions concerning the genealogy of the Plaut family. Letters between Elizabeth Strauss Plaut and family members additionally contain personal information on family members and events. Other papers found in this subseries include family trees and notes concerning the research into the Plaut family, as well as some photocopies of records pertaining to Plaut ancestors. Clippings on several members, including Elizabeth Plaut's husband and son, will also be found among the papers of this subseries. A memoir from an unidentified member of the Ornstein family includes reminiscences of time spent in concentration camps.
    - A) Correspondence
      - Abrams, Ifamar, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Beth Hatefutsoth Museum of the Jewish Diaspora Genalogical Center (Tel Aviv), 1980-1991 (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Beth Hatefutsoth Museum of the Jewish Diaspora Genalogical Center (Tel Aviv) - Jacobson, Jane, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Blauth Family Members, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 63)
        Blauth, Ruth 1982
        Blaut, Mr. [Unidentified] 1983
        Maccary, Olga 1977
        Peck, Mr. [Unidentified] 1977
      - Central Archives for the History of the Jewish People, 1976-1989 (Box 6, Folder 64)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees - Louis Plaut Branch, 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 66)
        Plaut, David 1977-1978
        Plaut, Julius 1978